My name's Conan Edogawa!
اسمي إيدوغاوا كونان
High school student Shinichi was forced to take a drug that shrunk him!
أُجبر طالب الثانوية كودو شينتشي على تجرّع عقار قلص جسده
Although smaller, my mind remains that of a sharp detective!
،رغم أنّي أصبحت أصغر !لا يزال عقلي عقل متحرٍّ عظيم
Today's case is on location for a TV drama!
مسرح قضيّة اليوم هو موقع تصوير دراما تلفزية
No matter how good an actor is, there is always only one truth!
!مهما كان الممثل بارعاً، تبقى الحقيقة واحدة دوماً
The TV Drama Murder Case.
جريمة قتل الدراما التلفزية
Beika Shrine
ضريح بيكا
No...
...لا يمكن
I never meant to kill you!
...لم أنوِ قتله
Cut!
!اقطع
Okay! That's it for this scene!
حسنٌ، هذه نهاية المشهد
That was some fine acting, Yoko!
كان تمثيلاً ممتازاً يا يوكو
Filming a TV drama is interesting, don't you think?
تصوير دراما تلفزية أمرٌ مثير، ألا تتفق؟
Yeah!
!بلى
Popular Idol Okino Yoko (21)
فنّانة مشهورة (أوكينو يوكو (21
Thank you!
شكراً جزيلاً
Leading Man Nachi Shingo (23)
الممثل البطل (ناتشي شينغو (23
As if the great leading man Nachi Shingo would ever mess up!
مُحال للممثل النجم البطل ناتشي !شينغو أن تشوبه شائبة
Yoko-chan! You must be exhausted!
!يوكو-تشان! عملٌ رائع
Thank you, Mori-san!
شكراً يا موري-سان
What an amazing performance that was!
!كان تمثيلاً بديعاً
I'm absolutely certain that this drama will go down as a masterpiece!
!ستصبح هذه الدراما تحفة فنّية دون أدنى شك
But only because you helped supervise the mystery writing!
سيكون ذلك بفضل مساعدتك لنا في الإشراف على نصوص الغموض
That's right!
إنّها محقة
We have with us the famous detective who's known
معنا المتحرّي الشهير الذي يُعرف
as the modern-day Akechi Kogoro!
بأنّه أكيتشي كوغورو هذا الزمان
This drama's going to be a smash hit, no doubt about it!
المخرج (كوندو تاكيتوشي (57
Well, I suppose I did help a lot!
لعلّي ساعدت نوعاً ما
He's on top of the world now...
إنّه بأفضل مزاج الآن
This goes here, and this goes like this...
...هذه هكذا، وهذه هنا
Way too easy...
سهلةٌ جداً
Hey, you!
!أنت
Don't be touching my things!
!لا تلمس أغراضي
I'm sorry, Nachi-san!
آسفة يا ناتشي-سان
I wasn't paying close enough attention to him...
لم أنتبه له كما يجب
Well, I guess I can forgive him if it's for a cute girl like you...
ر-ربما يمكنني مسامحته لأجل فتاة ظريفة مثلك
Thank you!
!شكراً
Bah. What a smooth talker.
يا للمتملق
You're into matchstick puzzles, Nachi-san?
أتحبّ حل أحجيات أعواد الثقاب يا ناتشي-سان؟
Yes, leading men like me prefer intelligent hobbies.
أجل، فالأبطال مثلي يميلون للهوايات الفكرية
Oh, is that so?
أحقاً ذلك؟
Nachi-san! Good work today!
!ناتشي-سان! عملٌ موفق
Continuity Checker Mamegaki Taeko (24)
مشرفة النصّ (ماميغاكي تايكو (24
Here's a towel!
تفضّل منشفة
Say, would you have dinner with me tonight?
ما رأيك بأن نتناول العشاء معاً الليلة؟
Sorry, I can't!
آسفة
Oh, come on!
أين المشكلة؟ لن نطيل
She can't.
لا يمكنها
She and this kid are getting hitched next month.
فهي ستتزوج هذا الشاب الشهر المقبل
Ain't that right, Shimazaki?
صحيح يا شيمازاكي؟
Assistant Director Shimazaki Yuji (26)
المخرج المساعد (شيمازاكي يوجي (26
Yeah...
...أجل، صحيح
Really?! Congratulations!
!حقاً؟! تهانينا
Thanks!
!شكراً
They only seem like flowers before you marry them.
هُنّ كالأزهار قبل الزواج فقط
You don't know it's an illusion until it's too late.
لا تدرك أنّه سراب إلّا بعد فوات الأوان
What?!
!ماذا؟
No, Yuji-san!
!كلا يا يوجي-سان
He always has something bad to say!
!يتفوّه بكلامٍ مهين دوماً
It's just what people say. I'm not necessarily talking about you.
هذا كلامٌ عام، لم أكن أوجّهه لكما بالضبط
Don't get so upset.
لا تغضب هكذا
It's my watch's alarm.
إنّه منّبه ساعتي
Cool sound, huh? I bought it last month when I went to America.
صوتٌ مثير، صحيح؟ اشتريتها الشهر الفائت عندما سافرتُ إلى أمريكا
Guess you don't care.
يبدو أنّكم لا تهتمون
See you chumps later.
أراكم لاحقاً
What a jerk...
يا للبغيض
One, two, three...
واحد، اثنان، ثلاثة
Are they finished filming?
هل انتهى التصوير؟
Yes, Grandfather.
جدّي
Make sure to clean everything up before you leave.
تذكّروا تنظيف كّل شيء قبل المغادرة
Especially things like that.
أشياء كتلك بالتحديد
We will, Grandfather!
نفهم يا جدّي
I leave it in your hands.
أعتمد عليك
Your grandfather is the shrine keeper here?!
جدّك هو المسؤول عن الضريح هنا؟
Yes, this shrine is where I grew up.
أجل، هذا الضريح الذي ترعرعت فيه
Hey, Ran-neechan...
ران-نيتشان
Didn't your friend ask you to get Nachi Shingo's autograph?
ألم يطلب أصدقاؤك توقيع ناتشي شينغو؟
I forgot!
!نسيت
Where is he?!
أين ناتشي-سان؟
Already went to change clothes.
ذهب لتغيير ثيابه قبل فترة
Oh no!
!كلا
Wait a sec, Ran-neechan!
!ا-انتظري، ران-نيتشان
Cut the crap!
!يكفي هراءً
That's Nachi-san's voice...
...كان ذلك صوت ناتشي-سان
Do you even have any proof?!
ألديك دليلٌ حتّى؟
Of course I do.
بالطبع
If you want these photos and negatives, you know what to do.
،إن أردتَ هذه الصور الملونة والسلبية تعرف ما عليك فعله
Money?!
مال؟
What's the matter?
ما الخطب؟
No, nothing at all!
!كلا، لا شيء
Mori-san. We'll be staying at this inn tonight.
موري-سان، سنقضي الليلة في هذا النُزل
How about a nice bath and a drink?
ما رأيك بحمّامٍ مريح وشراب؟
Sounds good to me!
!يبدو رائعاً
Give me a break, Dad...
...أبي، يا إلهي
Ran-san and Conan-kun should come too!
انضما لنا يا ران-سان وكونان-كن أيضاً
Sure!
!أجل
What a crappy-looking inn!
!يا للنُزل رديء المظهر
A leading man such as me would never stay in a place like this!
لن يقيم بطلٌ مثلي في مكانٍ كهذا
This constant talk about being a leading man is really annoying...
...لا يكفّ عن الكلام عن بطوليّته، كم هو مزعج
I'll be staying at the Teitan Hotel.
سأبقى في فندق تيتان
Wait, Nachi-san!
!لـ-لحظة، ناتشي-سان
He's hopeless...
...لا أمل معه
Drink up, Mori-san!
!اشرب يا موري-سان
Sorry for the wait!
شكراً لانتظاركم
Hey, Anzai! Where you goin'?
أنزاي! أين تذهب؟
The camera doesn't keep itself tuned up, you know.
عليّ ضبط الكاميرا
What an unfriendly fellow.
كم هو انعزاليّ
Yuji-san. I need to take care of something at home...
يوجي-سان، عليّ التكفل بأمرٍ في المنزل
Okay. Hurry back.
حسناً، فهمت. عودي سريعاً
You don't need make-up, Ran-san! You're still young!
لا تحتاجين لمساحيق التجميل !يا ران-سان، لا تزالين يافعة
That's Shimazaki-san!
شيمازاكي-سان
Hey, Shimazaki! Get me some cigarettes while you're out.
!شيمازاكي! اجلب لي سجائر معك
Sure thing!
فهمت
Say, Ran-san! Let's go to the convenience store!
هلّا رافقتني للبقالة يا ران-سان؟
But isn't it a bad idea for an idol to walk outside at night?
لكن أليس من السيّئ أن تتجوّل فنانة في وقت متأخر؟
I'll be fine!
لا بأس
Nobody'll recognize me if I change my hairstyle and wear a hat!
لن يعرفني أحد إن غيّرتُ تسريحتي !وارتديت قبعة
I saw them changing!
رأيتهما يبدّلان ملابسهما
Yoko-san. Are you really sure this is okay?
أأنتِ متأكدة لا مشكلة في هذا يا يوكو-سان؟
Of course!
أجل
It looks like Anzai-san's going out too...
يبدو أنّ أنزاي-سان سيخرج أيضاً
You worry too much, Ran-san!
أنتِ كثيرة القلق يا ران-سان
Huh?
ماذا؟
Taeko-san...
تايكو-سان
Taeko-san!
!تايكو-سان
Oh, Ran-san!
!ران-سان
Is something the matter?
أهناك خطبٌ ما؟
No...
...كـ-كلا
I wonder what that was about...
ما كان ذلك يا ترى؟
She looked like she had seen a ghost...
بدت كأنّها رأت شبحاً
Thank you!
!شكراً
See? I told you we'd be fine!
رأيتِ؟ أخبرتك لا مشكلة
You were right! They didn't recognize you at all!
!معكِ حق! لم يعرفوك أبداً
Who was that?!
!من ذاك؟
Don't tell me it was an offering thief!
!أيمكن أنّه سارق تبرّعات؟
There's someone on the ground!
!هناك شخصٌ على الأرض
Anzai-san!
!أنزاي-سان
He's dead! Call the police!
!إنّه ميت! اتّصلوا بالشرطة
Hurry!
!بسرعة
Right!
!أجل
Even if the victim's hat fell off when he collapsed,
،حتّى لو سقطت قبعة الضحية مع سقوطه
how did his vest come off?!
كيف نُزعت سترته؟
This is the knife they used during filming!
هذه... السكّين التي اُستعملت في التصوير
Which means that the killer was someone on the filming crew!
مما يعني أنّ القاتل أحد العمّال
Shinto Statue
تمثال كوما إينو
This is a dying message the victim left behind!
!هذه رسالة احتضار تركها الضحيّة
"Shinto Statue?"
(كوما إينو؟ (كلب أسد
Is this a clue to who did it?!
أيشير هذا لهويّة الفاعل؟
You saw someone suspicious before you found the body, correct?
رأيتم شخصاً مريباً قبل عثوركم على الجثّة، صحيح؟
Yes. But it was too dark to even tell if it was a man or a woman.
أجل، منعنا الظلام من معرفة إن ما كان رجلاً أو امرأة
And that was around 10:30.
وكان ذلك عند العاشرة والنصف
That means the murder took place between 10:00
مما يعني أنّ الجريمة وقعت بين العاشرة
and when the victim left the inn at 10:30.
وبعد مغادرة الضحيّة النُزل حتى العاشرة والنصف
Inspector. This case is surprisingly simple.
سيدي المفتش، هذه القضية بمنتهى البساطة
How's that?
لمَ؟
First off, the murder weapon was used during the show's filming.
أوّلاً، اُستعمل سلاح الجريمة في تصوير الدراما
Second, "Shinto Statue" clearly refers to the Shinto Shrine.
وثانياً، تشير كوما إينو إلى ضريح شينتو
From these two facts alone...
...مما يعني من هذين الأمرين
...the killer must be you, Mamegaki Taeko-san!
!المجرم هو أنت يا ماميغاكي تايكو-سان
Nonsense! Taeko would never kill anyone!
!هراء! لن تجرؤ تايكو على قتل أحد
Taeko-san. You were gone for nearly an hour during the party, correct?
،كنتِ متغيّبةً لقرابة ساعة أثناء الحفلة صحيح يا تايكو-سان؟
I needed to get something at home...
كان عليّ البحث عن شيء في المنزل
Our house is behind the shrine.
فهو خلف الضريح
Can anyone verify that you were there?
أهناك من يشهد على وجودك؟
Grandfather was out at the time, so I was the only one there...
كان جدّي خارجاً، فكنتُ بمفردي
But Taeko-san came back just as Anzai-san left the inn!
لكنّ تايكو-سان عادت مع مغادرة أزاي-سان للنُزل يا أبي
What?!
!ماذا؟
After she came back, she stayed in the hall the whole time...
بقيت في الرواق طوال الوقت بعد عودتها
That means she couldn't possibly have killed him.
أي يستحيل أن تكون من ارتكبت الجريمة
Get a hold of yourself, will ya?!
اضبط عقلك
Any fingerprints on the murder weapon?!
أهناك بصمات على سلاح الجريمة؟
No. But it looks like someone wiped them away.
كلا، لكن هناك آثار لإزالة أحدهم لها
That's weird!
غريب
If the killer had time to wipe the fingerprints off,
إن كان للقاتل وقت كافٍ لإزالة البصمات
why not run off with the murder weapon instead?!
فلمَ لم يأخذ سلاح الجريمة معه؟
Did anyone among you leave the inn between 10:00 and 10:30?
أبينكم من غادر النُزل بين العاشرة والعاشرة والنصف؟
Um... I went to buy cigarettes.
أنا ذهبتُ لشراء السجائر
When was this?
متى كان ذلك؟
Let me think...
...في الواقع
9:45!
التاسعة وخمسٌ وأربعون
I happened to look at my watch just then!
صادف أن نظرتُ للساعة ذاك الوقت
And when did you return?
ومتى رجعت؟
About 30 minutes later.
نصف ساعة بعدها
Which would be 10:15?
أيّ عند العاشرة والربع؟
Yes.
أجل
Tell me, Nachi-san.
بالمناسبة يا ناتشي-سان
I hear you were the only one who decided to stay at the Teitan Hotel
سمعت أنّك الوحيد الذي اختار الإقامة في فندق تيتان
instead of this inn.
بدل هذا النُزل
My pride as a leading man wouldn't let me stay in such a hovel!
لن يسمح لي فخر البطل بأن أقيم في كوخٍ كهذا
Where were you between 10:00 and 10:30?
أين كنت بين العاشرة والعاشرة والنصف؟
I was in the hotel bar until 10:00.
كنتُ في حانة الفندق حتى العاشرة
Plenty of people can vouch for me.
يوجد الكثير من الشهود
I'm asking about after that!
أسألك عمَّا بعدها
I was in my hotel room.
كنتُ في غرفتي
Can anyone verify this?
أهناك شهود؟
I was by myself, so no!
!كنتُ بمفردي، لذا لا
The killer's someone on the filming crew...
...القاتل أحد العمّال في الدراما
Our only clue is the phrase "Shinto Statue," which the victim wrote...
الخيط الوحيد هو عبارة كوما إينو التي كتبها الضحية
Taeko-san is the one most closely connected to Shinto statues...
تايكو-سان هي الأقرب صلةً بتماثيل كوما إينو ظاهرياً
But she returned to the inn just as the victim was leaving it.
لكنّها عادت للنُزل مع مغادرة الضحيّة له
Come to think of it...
...صحيح
...why was she so surprised then?!
لمَ كانت الدهشة تغلب ملامحها آنذاك؟
Shimazaki-san went to buy cigarettes at 9:45
ذهب شيمازاكي-سان لشراء السجائر عند التاسعة وخمس وأربعون
and returned to the inn at 10:15.
ثمّ عاد للنزل عند العاشرة والربع
More than enough time to commit the murder.
لديه وقت كافٍ لارتكاب الجريمة
But it was 10:30 when we saw the person at the shrine.
لكنّنا رأينا صورة الشخص عند الضريح في العاشرة والنصف
Shimazaki-san was back at the inn by then.
وكان شيمازاكي-سان قد عاد للنُزل
Nachi-san has no alibi after 10:00-- he could have done it as well.
،لا يملك ناتشي-سان حجّة غياب بعد العاشرة فيمكن أنّه ارتكبها أيضاً
It sounded like he was being blackmailed by the victim,
بدا أنّه يتعرض للابتزاز من الضحية
so in terms of motive, he's the most suspicious.
لذا فهو الأكثر شبهةً من ناحية الدافع
And Nachi-san was most likely the one we saw in the shadows!
وبنيته هي الأقرب للشخص الذي رأيناه في الظلام
Inspector! We found these in the victim's room!
سيّدي المفتش، وجدنا هذه في غرفة الضحية
Nachi-san... This is you leaving a hotel with a woman...
هذه... صورتك وأنت تغادر الفندق مع امرأة يا ناتشي-سان
That's the actress Hagiyama Ritsuko!
!هذه المرأة هي الممثلة هاغياما ريتسوكو
But she's married!
!لكنّها متزوجة
Photographic evidence of your infidelity...
صور تدين علاقتك غير الشرعية
Now that you mention it!
...تـ-تذكرت
Do you know something, Ran?!
أتعرفين شيئاً يا ران؟
I saw Anzai-san trying to blackmail Nachi-san earlier!
رأيتُ أنزاي-سان يبتزّ ناتشي-سان قبل هبوط الظلام
Blackmail?!
!يبتزّ؟
So you are the killer!
!أنت القاتل إذاً
I already told you, I didn't do it!
!أخبرتك كلا
If I killed him, then what the hell does "Shinto Statue" mean?!
!إن كنتُ القاتل فما معني كوما إينو؟
You sure that's not one of your nicknames?
أليس أحد ألقابك؟
You idiot!
!أحمق
No leading man like me would have a crappy nickname like that!
لن يرضى بطلٌ مثلي !بلقب سخيفٍ كهذا
What exactly does this "Shinto Statue" mean?!
ما المقصود بـ كوما إينو هذه بالضبط؟
Wait a second!
لحظة
Why would he go through the trouble of writing it down?!
لمَ تكبّد عناء كتابة الرموز؟
He was killed right in front of a Shinto statue--
فقد قُتل أمام تمثال كوما إينو مباشرةً
all he had to do was point at it!
كلّ ما كان عليه هو توجيه إصبعه له
There was no need to write it out!
لم تكن هناك حاجة للكتابة
What's this?!
!هذا
Do you even have any proof that I was here?!
!ألديكم دليل أنّي كنت هنا أصلاً؟
Huh? This writing is weird!
!هذا الرمز غريب
This character isn't drawn right!
!ليس مكتوباً بشكل صحيح
That lousy kid's at it again!
!ذاك الشقيّ مجدداً
How many times do I have to--
...أنت! كم مرّةً أكرر كلامي
This man was an adult, but he couldn't even write katakana right!
هذا الرجل بالغ لكنه لم يعرف كتابة الكاتاكانا بشكل صحيح حتى
What did he draw wrong?
كتابتها بشكل صحيح؟
You're supposed to write this part here all in one stroke.
انظر، يُفترض أن تكتب هذا الحرف بحركة واحدة
But he wrote it using two.
لكنه فعل بحركتين
What now?!
!ماذا؟
You're right...
...أنتَ مُحق
He did the same with the last character too!
الأمر نفسه مع الرمز الأخير
What?!
!ماذا؟
What if these incorrect strokes were actually lines that were added later?!
أيمكن أنّ هذه الحركات الخاطئة قد أُضيفت لاحقاً؟
"Leading man"?!
!البطل؟
The only leading man around here is Nachi Shingo!
!البطل الوحيد هنا هو ناتشي شينغو
It looks like some definitive proof has shown itself.
يبدو أنّ الدليل الدامغ قد ظهر
No! It wasn't me!
!كـ-كلا! لم يكن أنا
I'll admit that I was supposed to meet Anzai here at 10:30,
كان يُفترض أن ألتقي أنزاي هنا عند العاشرة والنصف حقاً
but when I showed up, he was already dead!
!لكنه كان ميتاً في وقت وصولي
Enough of this tomfoolery!
!يكفي هراءً
It's the truth! He really was dead when I got here!
!إنّها الحقيقة! كان ميتاً بالفعل عندما أتيت
I was about to run away, but then I saw "leading man" written there...
كنتُ على وشك الهرب، لكني رأيت "البطل" مكتوبة
So I added some vertical lines like in the matchstick puzzles that I do!
فأضفت خطوط عامودية كما أفعل مع أحجيات أعواد الثقاب التي أحلّها
If you're not the killer, then why did the victim write "leading man"?
إذا لم تكن القاتل، فلمَ كتب الضحية "البطل"؟
Hell if I know!
!كيف لي أن أعرف؟
Wait a minute!
لحظة
It's not normal for someone to fake a dying message
ليس من الطبيعي أن شخصاً زيّف رسالة احتضار
but not come up with a fake alibi!
لم يجهز حجّة غياب مزيفة
Maybe the real killer altered the message to say "leading man"!
أيمكن أن القاتل الحقيقي من عدّل الرسالة لتكون "البطل"؟
Could this be what I think it is?!
!أيمكن أنّ هذا ما أعتقده؟
It couldn't have been that person!
مستحيل، لا يمكن أن يكون ذاك الشخص
What's that?!
...هذا
There's no blood on this watch!
!لا دم على على هذه الساعة
Aha! That's it!
!فهمت! هكذا إذاً
Now I know the truth behind this case!
!عرفتُ حقيقة هذه القضية
It wasn't me! I didn't do it!
!لم يكن أنا! لم أفعلها
Listen to how pathetic you sound, Mr. Leading Man!
منظرك بائس الآن أيّها النجم البطل
You can give us the details down at the station.
يمكنك الإدلاء بالتفاصيل في المركز
Not so fast!
!انتظروا
Inspector Megure. Nachi-san is not the murderer.
مفتش ميغوري، ناتشي-سان ليس القاتل
Come again?!
!ماذا؟
The reason being that the murder took place before 10:00!
فالجريمة قد وقعت قبل العاشرة
That's impossible!
!مستحيل
What are you talking about, Dad?
ما الذي تقوله يا أبي؟
We saw Anzai-san leave the inn around 10:00!
!رأينا أنزاي-سان يغادر النزل عند العاشرة
We even heard his watch alarm go off!
!كما سمعنا منبّه ساعة يده
Inspector. Have a look at the victim's wristwatch.
حضرة المفتش، انظر لساعة يد الضحية
His watch?
ساعة يده؟
His entire left arm is covered in blood,
ذراعه اليسرى تغطيها الدماء
but there's none at all on his watch.
لكن لا دم على ساعته
You're right!
!مـ-معك حق
In other words, someone removed the watch from the body
مما يعني أنّ أحدهم خلع الساعة من الجثّة
after the victim was killed!
بعد أن قُتل الضحية
Someone removed his watch?
خلع شخص ساعته؟
This particular person wanted to make it look like the murder happened
أراد ذاك الشخص أن يجعل وقت وقوع الجريمة
later than it actually did.
أبعد مما حصل
So the killer came up with the idea of taking the watch back to the inn
فخطرت له فكرة أخذ الساعة معه للنزل
and setting the alarm off in the victim's room.
وتفعيل المنبه في غرفة الضحية
But it would cause problems if blood dripped off it on the way back,
لكن ستكون مشكلةً لو تقطر الدم في طريق عودته
so the killer wiped the watch clean.
فنظّف الساعة تماماً
That means the person we saw at the inn was--
...أي أن من رأيناه في النزل
That's right. That wasn't Anzai-san.
أجل، لم يكن أنزاي-سان
The person who set the alarm off in Anzai-san's room
...من شغل المنبه في غرفة أنزاي-سان
put his vest and hat on and left the inn disguised as Anzai-san himself.
ارتدى السترة والقبعة وغادر بتنكّر أزاي-سان
This person rushed back to the shrine,
انطلق ذاك الشخص مسرعاً للضريح مجدداً
put the watch back on the dead body,
وأعاد الساعة للجثة
and then dropped the hat and vest nearby!
وترك القبعة والسترة بالقرب
Then the killer wrote "leading man" to make Nachi-san look guilty!
ثمّ كتب "البطل" لتوجيه التهمة نحو ناتشي-سان
If the killer wanted Nachi-san to look guilty,
،لو أراد الشخص توجيه التهمة لـ ناتشي-سان
why not just write "Nachi"?!
!فلمَ لم يكتب ناتشي فقط؟
That would have been a much more effective way of fooling us!
!كان ذلك سيضللنا بتأثير أكبر
The killer couldn't write "Nachi."
"لم يستطع القاتل كتابة "ناتشي
The reason being that the victim had already written something
فالضحية قد كتب بالفعل
that identified the murderer.
ما يدين القاتل
Something that identified the murderer?
ما يدين القاتل؟
That's right.
أجل
"Leading man" was actually a single word that the victim wrote,
البطل" كانت كلمةً كتبها الضحية"
with extra strokes added in later.
بخطوط إضافية كتُبت لاحقاً
Then what was the original word the victim wrote?!
...أي أن الكلمة التي كتبها الضحية في الأصل
It was "Mame."
إنّها... مامي
Mamegaki Taeko-san. You're the murderer.
ماميغاكي تايكو-سان، أنتِ القاتلة
Nonsense! She would never!
...مـ-مستحيل! لا يمكن أنّ تايكو
It couldn't be!
لا يُعقل
But Mori-san!
لكن موري-سان
Taeko-san returned to the inn just as the person disguised as Anzai-san left!
عادت تايكو-سان للنزل مع مغادرة الشخص الذي تنكّر كأنزاي-سان
It was me! I killed Anzai-san!
!كان أنا! أنا قتلت أنزاي
I was the one who dressed up as him!
!كنتُ من تنكر بهيئته
But the word "Mame" wasn't written there!
!لم تكن كلمة "مامي" مكتوبة
Shimazaki-san. You were indeed the one who dressed up as him,
،شيمازاكي-سان، كنتَ من قد تنكّر بهيئته فعلاً
but you cannot possibly be the killer.
لكن لستَ المجرم
See the huge spray of blood around the body?
ترون الدم المنتشر حول الجثة؟
The killer must have been covered in a lot of blood as well.
لا بدّ أنّ القاتل كانت تغطيه الدماء بدوره
But there's not even a single drop on your clothes.
لكن لا توجد أيّ قطرة على ثيابك
The only person who had time to change clothes and wash off the blood
الوحيدة التي كان لها وقت لتغيير ثيابها وغسل الدم
was Taeko-san!
هي تايكو-سان فقط
No! I killed him!
!كلا! أنا قتلته
Yuji-san. It's over.
يوجي-سان، انتهى الأمر
Taeko!
!تايكو
It's just as you said, Mori-san.
كما قال موري-سان
I killed Anzai-san.
أنا قتلتُ أنزاي
Taeko-san!
!تايكو-سان
No way!
!لا يمكن
I take it you didn't know Shimazaki-san had dressed up as him?
لم تعرفي أنّ شيمازاكي-سان تنكر بهيئته؟
No.
كلا
So I was really shocked when I saw Anzai-san at the front door...
لذا كنتُ مصدومةً عندما رأيتُ أنزاي عند مدخل النزل
I had no idea what was going on anymore.
لم أكن أملك فكرةً عمَّ يجري
But why, Taeko-san?!
!لكن لمَ يا تايكو-سان؟
Taeko-san. Anzai was blackmailing you too, wasn't he?
تايكو-سان، كان أنزاي يبتزك أيضاً، صحيح؟
Yes.
أجل
When I was in high school, I turned rebellious for a short time
عندما كنتُ في الثانوية، مررت بفترة تمرد لفترة قصيرة
after my parents died in an accident.
بعد موت والديّ في حادث
I stopped going to school and started hanging out with the wrong crowd...
توقفت عن ارتياد المدرسة وتسكّعت مع أشخاص سيّئين
Anzai was one of them.
كان أنزاي من ضمنهم
Grandfather.
جدّي
Remember when everyone was in an uproar
أتذكر الجلبة الكبيرة التي وقعت بعدما سُرق تمثال باهظ
after that expensive statue was stolen from the shrine storehouse?
من مخزن الضريح؟
Yes...
...أ-أجل
That was my fault.
كانت غلطتي
After I mentioned it to Anzai, he immediately went and stole it...
...فبعدما بحتُ بالأمر لأنزاي، سرقوه فوراً
What?!
!ماذا؟
Why didn't you tell me?!
!لمَ لم تخبريني وقتها؟
I tried to!
!حاولت
But Sugiyama-san, who was in charge of the storehouse,
لكن... سوغياما-سان الذي كان مشرف المخزن
felt responsible for it and killed himself!
شعر بالمسؤولية وانتحر
I was too scared to say anything after seeing that!
منعني الخوف من قول أيّ شيء بعد رؤية ذلك
After that, I quit hanging around Anzai and the others,
ومُذ آنذاك، توقفت عن مرافقة أنزاي وجماعته
and I started taking school seriously again.
وعدتُ للمدرسة بجديّة
I had nearly managed to suppress the memories of that detestable event!
كنتُ على وشك دفن ذكريات الحادثة البغيضة ونسيها
All I wanted was to marry Yuji-san and start a happy family!
كلّ ما أردتُه هو تزوّج يوجي-سان وتشكيل عائلة سعيدة
But then he showed up!
!لكنّه ظهر عندها
And then he tried to blackmail you.
وحاول ابتزازك
Yes.
أجل
He said that since I had been an accomplice,
قال أنّي كنت متواطئة في تلك الحادثة
I was just as responsible for Sugiyama-san's suicide!
وأتحمل جزءاً من انتحار سوغياما-سان
He told me over and over!
!لم يكفّ عن قول ذلك
I felt that if something wasn't done, he would ruin our marriage!
شعرتُ أنّه سيفسد زواجي إلّم أفعل شيئاً
I was supposed to pay Anzai some money here at 9:30 tonight.
كان يُفترض أن أدفع له نقوداً هنا الليلة عند التاسعة والنصف
But instead, I brought a knife and threatened Anzai back!
!لكني جلبت سكّيناً بدل ذلك لردّ تهديد أنزاي
I told him never to show his face around me ever again!
!أخبرته بألّا يظهر أمامي مجدداً
He got mad and rushed for me...
...لكنه غضب ثمّ هاجمني
...and then the knife just happened to--
...وعندها السكين اخترقت
I never meant to kill him!
...لم أنو قتله
You seemed strange when you left, so I pretended to go buy cigarettes.
،أثرتِ قلقي بملامحك عند مغادرتك فتظاهرت بشراء السجائر وذهبت للضريح
When I got to the shrine, Anzai was dead,
ووجدتُ أنزاي ميتاً
and the word "Mame" was written in blood next to him.
و"مامي" مكتوبة بدمه
I figured you were the one who killed him,
ظننتُ أنّك من قتله
so I tried my hardest to alter all the evidence!
!فبذلت قصارى جهدي لمحو الأدلّة
I wiped the fingerprints off the knife,
مسحت البصمات عن السكّين
and took Anzai's watch back to the inn!
وأعدت ساعة أنزاي معي للنُزل
The rest is exactly as Mori-san deduced.
الباقي كما استنتج موري-سان
I should've just gotten rid of that writing in blood!
كان عليّ إزالة رسالة الدم كليّاً
But then I remembered how he threatened Nachi-san earlier this evening,
لكن تذكرت أنّه هدّد ناتشي-سان مساء اليوم
so I made "Mame" say "leading man" instead!
"فحوّلت "مامي" إلى "البطل
I'm so sorry, Yuji-san! Forgive me!
!آسفة يا يوجي-سان! آسفة
Taeko!
!تايكو
This door was locked!
كانت هذه الغرفة مغلقة
He may have killed himself!
لعلّه أقدم على الانتحار
Nope. This was a murder!
كلا، كانت جريمة قتل
You're in the way again?!
!أنتَ مُجدداً
Look closely at the doorway!
أمعن النظر لإطار المدخل
The murderer is among the seven of you!
!المجرم أحدكم السبعة
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
The Luxury Liner Murders, Part 1.
سلسلة جرائم قتل السفينة السياحية الفاخرة الجزء الأوّل
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
A piece of bread.
كسرة خبز